Marc Lafratta

Toronto, Ontario

marclafratta@gmail.com

Profile

A senior full stack web developer with a back end focus experienced in building complex client facing integrated sites at large financial institutions and in startup environments. Strengths include building web services and integration points, working across technical and business teams, and taking ownership of a project through to successful production deployment.

Skills

- Ruby on Rails
- Java
- JavaScript
- C

- Rest integrations
- Docker
- Web Services
- AWS, IBM Cloud
- Client success
- Mentorship
- Recruiting
- Project leadership

Professional Experience

Sr. Software Engineer

Jul 2019 - Present

Humi HR

- Building integrated HR and Payroll solutions for Canadian SMBs in Ruby on Rails back end with an Angular front end
- Adding creating new features for a complex payroll system that adheres to provincial and federal regulations
- Integrating HR and Payroll systems to provide seamless workflows to both company admin and employee users
- Leading projects with PM and designer from requirements to continuos delivery
- Building a culture of knowledge sharing among remote team members through peer presentations and recurring update sessions

Back End Developer

Jun 2018 - Jul 2019

Ample Organics

- Developing solutions for Canada's leading software solution for cannabis Licensed Producers (LPs) using Ruby on Rails backend with Backbone/Marionette/VueJS and Angular front-ends
- Developing features including changes to JS front end apps and Rails back end
- Defined and implemented integration point between Ample and Shopify allowing LPs to process compliant medical sales using Shopify stores
- Solving complex data and code issues identified by the customer support team
- Optimizing reporting system that fulfills regulatory and business needs
- Recruiting and selecting new members of the technical team
- Mentoring junior team members on new software platforms and existing systems

Marc Lafratta

Toronto, Ontario marclafratta@gmail.com

Sr. Full Stack Web Developer (Technical Systems Analyst)

Aug 2015 – Jul 2017

RBC - Canadian Banking

- Created and improved features of the client facing retail online banking web application
- Developed services in Java EE on Webpshere and pages on Cloud Foundry with Spring MVC and mainframe with Websphere Portal with pure JS/JQuery active front ends
- Directed technical team updating RBC's most used pages on the Online Banking portal
- Owned technical deliverables of a 10-person team from requirements to production release to 5 million clients
- Communicated directly with external vendors and internal middleware throughout the SDLC and advised business units on how our applications could best fulfill their needs
- Lead process of recruiting and selecting development full time and coop candidates for our team
- Onboarded and mentored new team members while delivering projects

Full Stack Web Developer (Technical Systems Analyst)

Aug 2013 – Aug 2015

RBC - Canadian Banking

- Quickly learned the complex existing systems in use across multiple platforms
- Updated several core Online Banking pages to meet accessibility standards
- Evangelized technical strengths of our team at university recruiting events
- Gold RBC Performance award 2014

Education

Bachelor of Software Engineering and Management

2005 - 2011

McMaster University

• Five-year program with the core requirements from the Commerce program

Other Experience

Vice President Internal, McMaster Engineering Society

2009 - 2010

- Managed communication and internal affairs in the MES and communication
- Coordinated activities between department clubs and chaired First Year Club

Canadian University Software Engineering Conference

2008 - 2011

Lead the McMaster University delegation as Head Delegate in 2011